# **Brendan MacCabe**

Data Solutions Specialist \* Data CRM \* CDP's \* Data Visualisation \* Data Insight

## **PROFILE:**

 Looking to take next step as a data specialist delivering expertise and business solutions in the fields of CRM, campaign management, CDP's, data visualisation, consumer insight, targeting and customer segmentation. Leveraging 20+ years of data analyst and CRM manager experience to deliver quality, efficiency and real business impact.

## **CAREER PATH:**

- In March 2024, departed role as CRM & Data Insight Manager for EDF and seeking next step in the field of data driven solutions for business.
- Career experience includes both extensive technical hands on delivery and senior team leadership for CRM and marketing functions.
- Most recent role with EDF responsible for a CRM team of 15 data professionals across UK and India, serving an extensive range of customer data solutions to meet objectives of retention, upsell, acquisition, account management and company obligations.

#### CONTACT

- 07967787517
- brendanmaccabe@gmail.com
- **Website**
- LinkedIn
- P Brighton, UK.

## **SKILLS & INTEREST**

- CRM campaign solutions
- Campaign tools & CDPs
- Data Visualisation
- · Consumer Insight
- Targeting & Segmentation
- Customer contact strategy
- Database Management
- Al evolution
- A First Class Honours degree in IT & data field, and range of data analyst positions prior to 12 years in a senior manger leadership role, all concerned with precise, effective and high performing customer data solutions.
- Extensive experience of delivering quality data products across the marketing campaign life cycle, including communication deployment, consumer insight, data visualisation, campaign design, customer segmentations, audience targeting & performance reporting.
- In 2023/24, particular interest in campaign strategy, optimisation and efficiency, further developing data solutions with data science, machine learning and following closely the evolution of AI in business.

## **CAREER HISTORY**

- EDF
  - Senior CRM & Data
     Insights Manager
     Oct 2021 March 2024
  - Senior CRM Manager
     Sep 2016 Sep 2021
  - Customer DataManagerJan 2010 Aug 2016
- Senior CRM team manager leading a virtual team of 15 data and insight analysts with 10 analysts in India + 5 at multiple UK locations.
- Provision of data driven campaign solutions, serving a wide range of business objectives within our Retail, Operational and Marketing teams.
- Solutions for c. 60 mil comms delivered in 2023, and responsible for c. 700 mil comms during EDF tenure as analyst + manager.
- Data selection, segmentation & deployment to customer and prospect audiences across email, DM, outbound, SMS & digital contact channels.
- Relationship owner with key suppliers including TCS India (offshore CRM team resources), CACI (data targeting products), HCL (campaign tooling).
- Data relationship owner for key business projects including campaign tool reviews, system / database migrations and acquisition of external datasets.
- Design and build of 30+ Tableau data visualisation solutions for effective campaign targeting, data insights and performance reporting enabling marketers quick access to information for campaign design and insights.
- Data Science model integrations for campaign targeting.
- Campaign consultant for effective targeting approaches, channel strategy and journey design for high performing campaigns.
- Lead for data quality, DPA, GDPR and compliance for CRM data solutions.
- Hands on design and build of campaign selections, customer segmentations and targeting models (eg. Cost of living crisis, Covid vulnerability models).

	<ul> <li>Self briefed insight deep dives - eg. campaign contact levels, customer vulnerability, smart meter lifestage - for knowledge share with marketing teams to optimise campaign targeting and performance.</li> <li>Demographic and behavioural data expertise with extensive knowledge and use of individual &amp; address level UK datasets (60 mil &amp; 27 mil records).</li> <li>JIRA project management and agile ways of working to manage challenging workloads that require continual and effective prioritisation.</li> </ul>
RAPP UK     Senior Data Analyst     Sep 2009 – Dec 2009	<ul> <li>Digital marketing agency role responsible for design, build and deployment of daily / weekly email marketing campaigns with Alterian campaign.</li> <li>Clients include Post Office, Lovefilm &amp; Cancer Research UK.</li> </ul>
EDF     Senior Data Analyst     Jan 2004 - Aug 2009	<ul> <li>Campaign design, build and deployment for EDF marketing campaigns across channels of email, DM, outbound telesales.</li> <li>Marketing and service communications to 3 mil EDF customer base and data solutions for c. 20 mil comms per year.</li> <li>Oracle database, SQL / TOAD programming.</li> </ul>
Thales Sensors Defence Oracle DBA Feb 2002 - Mar 2003	<ul> <li>Oracle database and MYSQL programming.</li> <li>Database design, build and maintain for company and customer datasets.</li> </ul>

TOOLS / SKILLS		
Oracle, Redshift, Snowflake	Data stores for organisation, access and views of industry, customer & prospect datasets, scheduled jobs to ensure safe and secure daily refresh routines.	
Campaign Tools & CDP's - HCL UNICA, Exponea, Blueshift.	Campaign journey design, build, test and deployment for multi channel customer communications and contact history stores with HCL UNICA. 2 years experience utilising Exponea and CDP tool reviews assessing Blueshift, Braze, AWS.	
SQL	20+ years experience of SQL programming for querying, creating, developing databases for campaign, insight & visualisation solutions.	
TOAD / Snowflake Web UI	Interface for efficient access, interrogation and views of customer datasets.	
Tableau	Hands on design, build & share of Tableau visualisations for effective data driven decision making to a marketing team user community of 100+ users.	
Matillion	Data transformations for effective data presentation and integrity, to enable effective campaign platform for UNICA solutions.	
Miro – Virtual Whiteboard	Effective share and presentation of information across team and stakeholders to assist team management, knowledge share and project coordination.	
JIRA	Task management for efficient control & delivery of individual / team workload and stakeholder management.	

EDUCATION	
First class degree - BSc Business Computing	Leeds Beckett University 1997 - 2001.
3 A-levels	Cardinal Newman High School - Sept 1990 - Jul 97.
9 GCSEs.	Cardinal Newman Sec. School - Sept 1997 - Jul 99.